- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[spooky music]
[诡异的音乐]
♪ ♪
[thunder booms]
[雷霆轰鸣]
- [panting, whimpering]
- [气喘吁吁，呜咽]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
♪ ♪
[doorknob rattling]
[门把手嘎嘎作响]
[loud thunking]
[重击声]
[screams]
- Grandma!
[尖叫声]
- 奶奶！
No!
[screams]
不！
[尖叫声]
- [laughs]
Get her, Grandma!
- [笑]
抓住她，奶奶！
[laughs, yelps]
[笑声，尖叫声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
I'm the ghost of Plankton!
我是浮游生物的幽灵！
Wooo!
[yelps]
呜呜！
[尖叫声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Hey, that gives me an idea.
嘿，这给了我一个主意。
[grunts]
[bright music]
[咕哝]
[明亮的音乐]
[Karen buzzes]
[babbles]
[凯伦嗡嗡声]
[胡言乱语]
Hmm, if I were a ghost,
嗯，如果我是鬼，
I could walk right through
the walls of the Krusty Krab
我可以直接走过
蟹堡王的墙壁
and take the Krabby Patty
secret formula!
吃蟹肉饼
秘密配方！
[giggles]
- Ah!
[咯咯笑]
- 啊！
All right, that's it.
好吧，就是这样。
You ruined another movie night
你又毁了一个电影之夜
with your
secret formula garbage.
与你的
秘方垃圾。
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
- I'm pulling the plug.
[whirrs down]
- 我要拔掉插头了
[呼啸而下]
- [groans] Ah.
Let's see.
- [呻吟]啊。
让我们来看看。
Now all I need to do
is invent a...
现在我需要做的就是
是发明一个...
[grunts]
Ghost extracting machine!
[咕哝]
鬼魂提取机！
[laughs, grunts]
[笑声，咕哝声]
[machine blipping, rattling]
[机器发出声音、嘎嘎声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[eerie music]
[诡异的音乐]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[whistles]
[口哨声]
I look like I just saw a ghost.
我看起来就像刚刚看到鬼一样。
♪ ♪
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
[laughs]
Success!
[笑]
成功了！
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
[laughs giddily]
[笑得眼花缭乱]
[hums, laughs]
[哼哼，大笑]
You gotta give up the ghost
if you wanna make toast.
你必须放弃幽灵
如果你想做吐司。
[grunts]
What?
[咕哝]
什么？
No, no, no!
不，不，不！
Stupid ghost hands!
愚蠢的鬼手！
[sobs]
[抽泣]
- [cackles maniacally]
- [疯狂地咯咯笑]
- What?
- 什么？
- [laughing hysterically]
- [歇斯底里地大笑]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[laughing continues]
[笑声继续]
- What's so funny?
Stupid ghost!
- 有什么好笑的？
愚蠢的鬼！
- You are, that's what.
- 你是，就是这样。
You can't just float in
on your first day
你不能只是漂浮在
在你的第一天
and pick things up.
并捡起东西。
[laughs]
[笑]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[chuckles]
[笑声]
Here you go.
Oh, grab it.
干得好。
哦，抓住它。
Grab it!
Get it! [laughs]
抓住它！
得到它！ [笑]
- I can't grab it!
- 我抓不到它！
[wheezes]
[喘息声]
- I like you, squirt.
- 我喜欢你，喷。
I got a soft spot
in me dead heart for thieves.
我有一个柔软的地方
我对盗贼已经死心了。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
- I can teach you
how to pick things up.
- 我可以教你
如何拾取东西。
- [squeals]
I love you.
- [尖叫声]
我爱你。
- But first, you need to learn
the "basics" of being a ghost.
- 但首先你需要学习
成为鬼魂的“基础”。
both: [laughs]
两人：[笑]
[bell gongs]
- [grunts, babbles]
[钟锣]
- [咕哝声，胡言乱语]
First lesson...
[wolf howls]
第一课...
[狼嚎]
Shape-shifting.
变形。
Shape-shifting is one
of the easiest things
变形是其中之一
最简单的事情
a ghost can do.
鬼也能做到。
You just have to think
of a horrible thing and poof!
你只需要思考
一件可怕的事情，噗！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[snake hisses]
[bat squeaks]
[蛇嘶嘶声]
[蝙蝠吱吱声]
[in Pearl's voice]
You become it!
[珍珠的声音]
你就成为它！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Now, you try.
- 现在，你试试。
- Hm...
- 嗯...
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[chicken clucking]
I did it!
[鸡咯咯叫]
我做到了！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
That's not horrible.
那并不可怕。
What were you thinking?
Bad ghost!
你在想什么？
坏鬼！
Bad!
- [groans]
坏的！
- [呻吟]
[coughs]
[咳嗽]
- Hmm.
Now, that's horrible!
- 唔。
现在，这太可怕了！
- Now can you teach me
how to pick things up?
- 现在你能教我吗
如何拾取东西？
- Not yet.
- 还没有。
- Hm?
[grunts]
- 嗯？
[咕哝]
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
- Next lesson, scaring.
- 下一课，吓人。
♪ ♪
Pay close attention, squirt.
仔细点，喷。
This is how you scare someone.
这就是你吓唬别人的方式。
- [chuckles mischievously]
- [cackling]
- [顽皮地笑]
- [咯咯笑]
[cat shrieking]
Huh?
[猫尖叫声]
啊？
Hm...
嗯...
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- [shrieks]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
- Okay, my turn.
- 好吧，轮到我了。
- [grunts softly]
- [轻声咕哝]
- Shh.
Someone's coming.
- 嘘。
有人来了。
Watch me scare this dummy
real good.
看我吓唬这个假人
真的很好。
[screams]
[thunder booms]
[尖叫声]
[雷霆轰鸣]
[shrieks]
[尖叫声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- Well, you scared yourself.
- 好吧，你吓到自己了。
I guess that counts.
我想这很重要。
Next lesson.
下一课。
- [shouts, whimpers]
- [喊叫，呜咽]
- Haunting houses.
- 鬼屋。
[thunder booms]
[雷霆轰鸣]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- All right, pupil, it's time
to apply all you've learned
- 好吧，学生，时间到了
运用你所学到的一切
and frighten
this guy's legs off.
并吓唬
这家伙的腿断了。
- With pleasure.
- 荣幸。
- Eh.
- 呃。
♪ ♪
[murmurs]
[低语]
[chuckles evilly]
[邪恶地笑]
- [screams]
Who's there?
- [尖叫]
谁在那里？
Ohh, is that you, SpongeBob?
哦，是你吗，海绵宝宝？
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
[gargles]
[漱口]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
[gasps]
[喘气]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- [grunts, babbles]
- [咕哝声，胡言乱语]
- [low groan]
- [低声呻吟]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
- Oooh.
- 哦。
Monster mouth with
a bucket of ghost goo--
怪物嘴与
一桶幽灵粘液——
very good marks.
非常好的分数。
[chuckles] Nice haunt, swabby!
[轻笑] 好地方，拭目以待！
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
[panting]
Oh, what a terrible nightmare.
[气喘吁吁]
噢，真是一场可怕的噩梦。
Oh, thanks for
being here, Clarry.
哦，谢谢你
在这里，克拉里。
You'll keep the monsters away.
[inhales]
你会让怪物远离你。
[吸气]
[lively tune playing]
【欢快的曲调演奏】
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- Give me that!
- 给我那个！
- Clarry!
[dramatic music]
- 克拉里！
[戏剧音乐]
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- [imitates SpongeBob's laugh]
- [模仿海绵宝宝的笑声]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- [laughing continues]
- [笑声继续]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
♪ ♪
[jaunty clarinet tune]
[欢快的单簧管曲调]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
- Hey, I picked something up!
- 嘿，我捡到东西了！
I can pick things up!
[vase crashes]
我可以捡东西！
[花瓶崩溃]
- Look at you.
- 看看你。
You skipped ahead
to the last lesson.
你跳过了前面
到最后一课。
- It's okay.
You don't have to--
- 没关系。
你不必——
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Last lesson!
- 最后一课！
How to pick things up.
怎么捡东西。
[eerie music]
[诡异的音乐]
As you discovered,
to pick things up,
正如你发现的那样，
去捡东西，
you gotta get really angry!
你一定要生气！
- Why didn't you say that
in the first place, moron?
-你为什么不这么说
首先，白痴？
- I have nothing
left to teach you.
- 我什么都没有
留下来教你。
- Oh, yeah?
- 哦，是吗？
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
[sniffling]
[emotional violin music]
[抽鼻子]
【情感小提琴音乐】
My boy.
我的男孩。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Oh, I'm really angry.
Here we go.
哦，我真的很生气。
开始了。
Yup.
是的。
[babbling]
[胡说]
Ah, ah.
Oh.
啊，啊。
哦。
Oh!
[laughs]
哦！
[笑]
[grunting]
[bottle clanking]
[咕噜声]
[瓶子叮当作响]
Blasted bottle!
It's always something!
瓶子被炸了！
总是有一些东西！
- [laughs]
- What?
- [笑]
- 什么？
- Guess you didn't think that
one through all the way, did ya?
- 我猜你没想到
一路走来，是吗？
- Dead jerk.
- 死混蛋。
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Well, I'm calling it.
- 嗯，我正在打电话。
This ghost racket
is for the birds.
这鬼球拍
是给鸟儿的。
I'm going back to my body
where I belong.
我要回到我的身体
我属于哪里。
Hmph!
哼！
- Hmm...
- 唔...
- Huh?
- 啊？
I don't remember
leaving the lights on.
我不记得了
让灯开着。
Wha--huh?
什——啊？
[somber music]
[忧郁的音乐]
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
Yeesh.
是啊。
You can't leave
your own carcass alone
你不能离开
唯有你自己的尸体
for ten minutes in this town!
在这个小镇待十分钟！
- And now,
if anyone has anything
- 现在，
如果有人有什么
nice to say about Sheldon,
this would be the time.
很高兴地说谢尔顿，
现在就是时候了。
- [snickers]
- Shh.
- [窃笑]
- 嘘。
♪ ♪
- Um, Plankton was small and...
[sniffs]
- 嗯，浮游生物很小而且......
[嗅嗅]
And green and loud!
又绿又响亮！
[sobbing hysterically]
[歇斯底里地抽泣]
- All right, come on.
- 好吧，来吧。
It's okay.
没关系。
- Yeesh.
- 是的。
This is the worst funeral
of mine I've ever been to.
这是最糟糕的葬礼
我曾经去过的。
But watch these idiots scream
when I get back in my body
但看看这些白痴尖叫
当我回到我的身体时
and jump out of that coffin.
然后跳出棺材。
- [cackles]
- [咯咯笑]
Ya can't go back
in your body now.
雅无法回去
现在在你的身体里。
You're dead, ya dodo!
你死定了，渡渡鸟！
- I'm not dead.
I'm just a temporary ghost.
- 我没有死。
我只是一个暂时的幽灵。
My body is in suspended
animation, that's all.
我的身体处于悬浮状态
动画，仅此而已。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
You mean,
this is an empty vessel?
你的意思是，
这是一个空容器？
I haven't possessed
a body in years!
我还没有拥有过
多年的身体！
- You can't do that!
That's my body!
- 你不能那样做！
那是我的身体！
- Not anymore!
- 不再！
- [whimpers] Huh?
- [laughs]
- [呜咽] 嗯？
- [笑]
♪ ♪
Rarg!
I'm alive!
拉格！
我还活着！
It's great to be back!
回来真是太好了！
all: [gasp]
- Oh!
全体：[喘气]
- 哦！
- No!
- 不！
- [giggles]
Ta-da!
- [咯咯笑]
哒哒！
- [sniffles]
Plankton's alive?
- [抽鼻子]
浮游生物还活着吗？
Hooray!
[yelps]
万岁！
[尖叫声]
- I knew it!
- 我就知道！
- He's alive?
[overlapping angry chatter]
- 他还活着吗？
[重叠的愤怒的喋喋不休]
- Let's squash him!
- 我们来压扁他吧！
all: [shouting angrily]
- ♪ Dee, dee, dee, dee ♪
全体：[愤怒地大喊]
- ♪ 迪伊，迪伊，迪伊，迪伊 ♪
♪ Da, da, dee, dee, dee, da ♪
♪ 达，达，迪，迪，迪，达 ♪
Wuh-oh.
[screams]
呃哦。
[尖叫声]
Eh?
Reowr?
呃？
重新写？
all: [growling]
全体：[咆哮]
- [yelping]
- [尖叫]
[whimpers, yelps]
[呜咽，尖叫]
- Oh!
- 哦！
I can't watch them
do that to me!
我无法看着他们
那样对我！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Here!
Take it.
这里！
拿走吧。
Those people are angry.
Whew!
那些人很生气。
哇！
I never thought I'd say this,
我从没想过我会说出这样的话
but I'd rather be a dead me
than an alive you.
但我宁愿做一个死去的我
比一个活着的你
Bye!
再见！
[yips]
[哎呀]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[groaning, grunting]
[呻吟，咕哝]
[sighs]
My body feels great!
[叹气]
我的身体感觉棒极了！
- There he is!
all: [growl]
- 他在那儿！
全体：[咆哮]
- [whimpers]
[laughs]
- [呜咽]
[笑]
Hey, everybody.
[nervous laugh]
嘿，大家。
[紧张的笑声]
Uh, who wants to hear
a ghost story, huh?
呃 谁想听
鬼故事吧？
[laughs] Anyone?
[笑]有人吗？
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
You know something?
Ooh!
你知道什么吗？
哦！
[grunting]
It's great to be alive.
[咕噜声]
能活着真是太好了。
[grunts, groans]
[咕哝声，呻吟声]
[grunting] Ouch!
[yelps]
[哼哼]哎哟！
[尖叫声]
[laughs]
[笑]
- The end!
- 结束！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[laughs]
[笑]